<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Other Notes on Yang Yan</title>
    <link>https://yan99.github.io/othernotes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Other Notes on Yang Yan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://yan99.github.io/othernotes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>3A</title>
      <link>https://yan99.github.io/othernotes/3a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yan99.github.io/othernotes/3a/</guid>
      <description>SLR Structure With half-silvered mirror down, some light is shunted to AF, remainder reflected up to form image on diffuse focusing screen AE and viewfinder sees from the same side of the mirror. AE light meter sees focusing screen; viewfinder sees with the same perspective as main sensor With mirror rotated up, light exposes to the main sensor. Taking pictures. Viewfinders Coverages and Magnification Coverage is fraction of sensor image covered by the viewfinder: $\frac{\text{area of focusing screen}}{\text{main sensor area}}$ Magnification is apparent size of objects in viewfinder relative to unaided eye: $\frac{\theta_{\text{viewfinder angle range}}}{\theta_{\text{eye angle range}}}$ Electronic viewfinders Pros: same view as lens without reflex mirror; tone map to show effect of chosen exposure Cons: poor resolution, low dynamic range relative to optical Tilt-shift Lenses Adjust the plane of focus to make the entire scene sharp Simulate a macro lens with a shallow depth of field, hence makes any scene look like a miniature model Not a tilt-shift lens, gradient blur can &amp;ldquo;fake&amp;rdquo; the tilt-shift lens effect Auto Focus Active or Passive: the position and directions of the illumination is known or unknown Active systems: some kind of radiation is send towards the scene (sonar, laser, structured light, etc.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
